<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alberto Cámara</title>
    <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alberto Cámara</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 08:00:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ber2.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Github Actions setup for Python projects in 2025</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/2025_github_actions_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 08:00:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/2025_github_actions_python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post I discuss my current choice of tools for setting up a Python project and running continuous integration via &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/features/actions&#34;&gt;Github Actions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In line with recent fashion, my choices revolve significantly around some of the recently introduced tools by &lt;a href=&#34;https://astral.sh&#34;&gt;Astral&lt;/a&gt;. Their common &lt;em&gt;leitmotiv&lt;/em&gt; is that, although designed for the Python ecosystem, the tools themselves are written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rust-lang.org/&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;. This, along with some very nice design decisions (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gSKTfG1GXYQ&#34;&gt;this talk&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;code&gt;uv&lt;/code&gt;, for example), makes them very reliable and fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting PyMC3 to work</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pymc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pymc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last few days, I have been diving into Cameron Davidson-Pilon&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;em&gt;Bayesian Methods for Hackers&lt;/em&gt;, available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CamDavidsonPilon/Probabilistic-Programming-and-Bayesian-Methods-for-Hackers&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book is an excellent, practical introduction to probabilistic programming and, more precisely, to the usage of &lt;strong&gt;Markov Chain Monte Carlo&lt;/strong&gt;, purely in Python and using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pymc-devs/pymc3&#34;&gt;PyMC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The printed version of the book was published a while ago and uses the PyMC library over Python 2.7.&#xA;Since then, the ecosystem has changed a bit, with the publication of &lt;strong&gt;PyMC3&lt;/strong&gt;, which updates the library to Python 3.&#xA;Although the Jupyter notebooks from the book have been updated to this context (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CamDavidsonPilon/Probabilistic-Programming-and-Bayesian-Methods-for-Hackers#pymc3&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), there have been further updates that require extra work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hashing documents during the Cookiepocalypse</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/simhash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/simhash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-floc-proposal&#34;&gt;The FLoC proposal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of their phasing-out of third party cookies and rolling out of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.google/products/ads-commerce/2021-01-privacy-sandbox/&#34;&gt;Privacy Sandbox&lt;/a&gt;, Google have announced their intentions to replace third party cookies in Chrome.&#xA;The strategy is to replace each of the functions served by third party cookies in web advertising, one by one, by individual devices that preserve user privacy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/WICG/floc&#34;&gt;Federated Learning of Cohorts&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;FLoC&lt;/strong&gt;) is the replacement for cross-site user tracking on Google Chrome.&#xA;In order to enable targeting based on browsing interests without cookie identifiers, the user&amp;rsquo;s browser computes a &lt;strong&gt;cohort identifier&lt;/strong&gt;, that is: a hash of the browsing history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BCN PyDay 2020 Counting votes with Dask</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pyday-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pyday-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have given a talk at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pybcn.org/events/pyday_bcn/pyday_bcn_2020/&#34;&gt;Barcelona PyDay 2020&lt;/a&gt;, which is taking place as an online event on&#xA;December 12th, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The title of the talk is &lt;strong&gt;Counting votes: analyzing a large dataset with Dask&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the&#xA;talk is to exhibit a use case in which &lt;a href=&#34;https://dask.org/&#34;&gt;Dask&lt;/a&gt; excels, in my opinion: working with&#xA;datasets which do not fit into single machine memory but still are reasonably small not to require&#xA;going to a cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing asyncio code on Python 3.9</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/asyncio-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/asyncio-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few notes on how to unit test Python asyncio code.&#xA;Accompanying code available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ber2/basic-asyncio-example&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pythons-asyncio-library&#34;&gt;Python&amp;rsquo;s asyncio library&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting from Python 3.7, and having received a lot of attention in subsequent releases, the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3/library/asyncio.html&#34;&gt;asyncio&lt;/a&gt; library provides a basis for comfortably&#xA;writing concurrent code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a good idea when you are given a task which is not CPU intensive, such that your program&#xA;will spend most of the time idly waiting for responses from other components. I/O bound tasks are&#xA;the typical example: when extracting data from a REST API, you are bound to spend most time sitting&#xA;on an idle CPU while waiting for HTTP responses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hourly Register</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/hourly-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/hourly-register/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;everybody-fill-up-forms&#34;&gt;Everybody fill up forms!&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;hourly register form&lt;/strong&gt; is a document which will be familiar to paid company workers in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduced by law a couple of years ago, it makes everyone register at which time they start and&#xA;stop working every day. A report is filled at the end of each month, signed and archived, and never&#xA;to be seen again unless the company suffers an inspection or a legal problem arises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On data classes in Python 3.8 and 3.9</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/dataclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/dataclasses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I gather a few comments and give some examples on the usage of &lt;strong&gt;data classes in Python&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-classes&#34;&gt;Data classes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3/library/dataclasses.html&#34;&gt;Data classes&lt;/a&gt; were introduced in Python 3.7.&#xA;We could summarize them as a convenient way to represent data, since classes decorated with&#xA;&lt;code&gt;@dataclass&lt;/code&gt; will supply methods such as &lt;code&gt;__init__()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;__repr__()&lt;/code&gt; without having to define them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parameter types are indicated using type annotations, so a data class declaration will look like&#xA;this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
