<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Data Ramblings</title>
    <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Data Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ber2.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting PyMC3 to work</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pymc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pymc/</guid>
      <description>In the last few days, I have been diving into Cameron Davidson-Pilon&amp;rsquo;s book Bayesian Methods for Hackers, available here.
The book is an excellent, practical introduction to probabilistic programming and, more precisely, to the usage of Markov Chain Monte Carlo, purely in Python and using PyMC.
The printed version of the book was published a while ago and uses the PyMC library over Python 2.7. Since then, the ecosystem has changed a bit, with the publication of PyMC3, which updates the library to Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hashing documents during the Cookiepocalypse</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/simhash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/simhash/</guid>
      <description>The FLoC proposal As part of their phasing-out of third party cookies and rolling out of the Privacy Sandbox, Google have announced their intentions to replace third party cookies in Chrome. The strategy is to replace each of the functions served by third party cookies in web advertising, one by one, by individual devices that preserve user privacy.
Federated Learning of Cohorts (FLoC) is the replacement for cross-site user tracking on Google Chrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Look</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/new-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 18:28:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/new-look/</guid>
      <description>As part of an ongoing experiment, I have stopped using jekyll and replaced it by hugo as build tool for this website.
I have also taken the chance to go for a dark theme called m10c, because I find dark themes easier on the eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BCN PyDay 2020 Counting votes with Dask</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pyday-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/pyday-talk/</guid>
      <description>I have given a talk at the Barcelona PyDay 2020, which is taking place as an online event on December 12th, 2020.
The title of the talk is Counting votes: analyzing a large dataset with Dask.
The purpose of the talk is to exhibit a use case in which Dask excels, in my opinion: working with datasets which do not fit into single machine memory but still are reasonably small not to require going to a cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing asyncio code on Python 3.9</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/asyncio-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/asyncio-testing/</guid>
      <description>A few notes on how to unit test Python asyncio code. Accompanying code available here.
Python&amp;rsquo;s asyncio library Starting from Python 3.7, and having received a lot of attention in subsequent releases, the asyncio library provides a basis for comfortably writing concurrent code.
This is a good idea when you are given a task which is not CPU intensive, such that your program will spend most of the time idly waiting for responses from other components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hourly Register</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/hourly-register/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/hourly-register/</guid>
      <description>Everybody fill up forms! The hourly register form is a document which will be familiar to paid company workers in Spain.
Introduced by law a couple of years ago, it makes everyone register at which time they start and stop working every day. A report is filled at the end of each month, signed and archived, and never to be seen again unless the company suffers an inspection or a legal problem arises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On data classes in Python 3.8 and 3.9</title>
      <link>https://ber2.github.io/posts/dataclasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ber2.github.io/posts/dataclasses/</guid>
      <description>In this post I gather a few comments and give some examples on the usage of data classes in Python.
Data classes Data classes were introduced in Python 3.7. We could summarize them as a convenient way to represent data, since classes decorated with @dataclass will supply methods such as __init__() or __repr__() without having to define them.
Parameter types are indicated using type annotations, so a data class declaration will look like this:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
